Guide to the Ralph Donnelly papers, 1838-1994 MS2057
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Ralph Donnelly papers
1838-1994
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Donnelly, Ralph
MS2057
3 Linear Feet
Collection contains correspondence, photographs, newsletters, maps, meeting minutes, reports, and surveys. This material convers the years 1954-94 and documents the activities of the C & O Canal Association and relate specifically to the C & O Canal.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
[required]
Biographical Note
Ralph Donnelly was an active member of the C & O Canal Association and one of the people who worked with Supreme Court Justice William O. Douglas to transform the long abandoned C & O Canal into a national park.
Ralph Donnelly spent sixty-six years as a surveyor. He graduated from Pennsylvania State University with a degree in civil engineering and a commission in the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers. He surveyed road and parks and designed bridges. In World War II, Major Ralph Donnelly, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, served in England, Scotland, France, Italy, Germany, and Austria. Licensed after the war as a professional surveyor in two states, Ralph Donnelly joined J.B. Ferguson & Co. of Hagerstown, Maryland. He retired five decades later as a senior partner. He was president of the Washington County, MD Historical Society, president of the Maryland Society of Surveyors, and vice-chairman of the Maryland Board of Registration.
Collection Scope and Content
This Collection contains correspondence, photographs, newsletters, maps, meeting minutes, reports, and surveys. This material convers the years 1954-94 and documents the activities of the C & O Canal Association and relate specifically to the C & O Canal.
Collection Organization
Organized into five series: C & O Canal Association, Publications, Miscellaneous, Oversized maps, blueprints, and other architectural information, and ephemera.
Washington (D.C.); Maps; Canals; Photographs; Chesapeake and Ohio Canal National Historical Park; Chesapeake and Ohio Canal (Md. and Washington, D.C.); Donnelly, Ralph; Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Association
- C & O Canal Association records, 1954-1994; MS2057 Series 1; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 1, Box 3, Box 2)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains correspondence, testimony, newspaper articles, reports, newsletters including "Along the Towpath" and "The Towline", meeting minutes, guidelines for level walkers, and by-laws. The material covers the dates 1954-94. These records were created during the course of business of the C & O Canal Association.
  - Reprint of Justice Douglas's letter to The Washington Post, and the editorial in reply to it accepting the invitation to hike the canal, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Print of the sheet signed by the hikers at the Cardinal Club at the end of the first days hike, 1954 March 20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter from Hancock C & 0 Canal Club to Subcommittee on Public Lands, 1959 March 21 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Invitations to dinner to be held at Hancock High School, 1959 March 25-April 25 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter to Jack Durham re boat captains and "doctoring boat", 1959 April 01 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Portion of Crowder's Towpath Guide reproduced for use by hikers from Sidling Hill Creek to Hancock Contains extensive annotations about all points along the route. List of level walkers attached.(earliest know list), 1959 April 23 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter of thanks to Ralph Donnelly from Justice William Douglas, 1959 April 27 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letter to Adele Donnelly from Orville Crowder regarding level walkers, 1959 May 03 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "The C&O Canal" article in Living Wilderness vol. 24 no. 68 by William O. Douglas, Spring, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letter to Ralph Donnelly from Wayne Aspinall Chairman Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs regarding H. R. 2331, 1959 June 01 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letter to Clarence Boyer from Ralph Donnelly regarding Maihon Boyer's bike trip on canal, 1959 June 22 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Orville Crowder memo on Level Walkers Hancock to Cumberland - with list of assignments, 1959 November 11 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Orville Crowder letter on inter-club week end for, 1959 December 23-1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Pamphlet Your Potomac - River Of Promise issued by Potomac River Development Association advocating hydroelectric dams on river, 1955-1959 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letter Edwin M. Dale (First Superintendent US Dept. of Interior NPS C&O Canal NHP Project Hagerstown City Hall to Mary Mish and reply letter regarding the brochure "That The Past Shall Live", 1960 February 28 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - The Level Walker vol.1 no.1, 1960 March (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Orville Crowder report to C&O Hostels Project Committee titled "Four Furious Days Upstream", 1960 April (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letter from Jack Durham regarding Sixth Reunion Hike, 1960 April 20-May 07 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Senate Bill 77 to establish the C & O Canal National Park, 1961 January 05 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Level Walker report Sidling Hill to Fifteen Mile Creek, 1961 March 12 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Letter from the President of the Hancock C&O Canal Club to the Chairman of the Committee on the Interior to Interior and Insular Affairs in support of S.77, 1961 April 10 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Testimony of Colin Ritter in favor of Canal Bill, 1961 April 10 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Testimony by Albert Herling (AFL-CIO) on S.B. 77., undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Testimony by Stewart Udall, Secretary of the Interior, on S.B. 77, 1961 April 12 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Testimony of Charles Robinson Jr. of the National Rural Electric Cooperative Association on S.B. 77. He was against the bill., undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Letter from Clinton Anderson, Chairman of the US Senate Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs to Ralph Donnelly, President of the Hancock C&O Canal Club, 1961 April 30 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - The Level Walker vol. 1 no.2, 1961 May (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Schedule for Seventh Annual Reunion Hike. (hike in rain thrown out of Anglers Inn), 1961 May 06 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Letter from J.L. Taylor, Chairman Middle Atlantic Division Association of American Geographers to Ralph Donnelly thanking for hike at Paw Paw Tunnel, 1961 May 08 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Amendment to By-Laws of the C&O Canal Association (increases board from 11 to 15), 1961 December 21 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Preliminary Alert for 1962 Reunion, 1962 February 21 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Letter from Jack Durham regarding meeting at Harpers Ferry to organize the1962 Reunion Hike, with committee list attached, 1962 March 09 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Letter from Durham-Crowder regarding 8th Annual Reunion Hike with reservation form. Canal song attached, 1962 April 13 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Mileage chart and sketch from the 8th Annual Reunion Hike. Washington Post photos attached, 1962 May 05-11 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Centennial Observer and C&O Canal Chronicle vol. 1 no. 6, Williamsport, MD, 1962 May 06 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - C&O Canal Association membership list, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Orville Crowder letter regarding preliminary information on the 1963 Reunion Hike, 1963 March 02 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Letter from Anson Courter regarding the Potomac Appalachian Trail Club hike on canal, 1963 April 03 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Orville Crowder letter regarding 9th Annual Reunion Hike. Mileage chart and timetable attached. Ribbon pinned to letter, 1963 April 06 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Washington Post article on 1963 Annual Reunion Hike, 1963 April 28 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Participant list of the 1963 9th Annual Reunion Hike (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Maryland Society of Professional Engineers 05/Meeting announces a talk by Ralph Donnelly titled "A Trip Along the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal,", 1963 May 03 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Letter from Mary Kovner of the Conservation Education Center to Ralph Donnelly regarding the talk given in Hagerstown, 1963 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Four depositions regarding land across canal at McCoys Ferrey, 1963 November 04 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Orville Crowder letter to Ralph and Adele Donnelly regarding the 10th Annual Reunion Hike, 1964 January 29 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Article "Life on the C&O Canal As Reported By a Voyager in 1859" in The Georgetowner vol. 7, no. 88, 1964 February 20 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - C&O Canal Association members and guests, 1964 March (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Colin Ritter letter regarding the 10th Annual Reunion Hike mileage table, reservation form, song, badge, and Washington Post article attached, 1964 April 01-21 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - C&O Canal Association 10th Annual Reunion Hike flier, 1964 April 19-25 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Program for 10th Annual Reunion banquet, 1964 April 25 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Article "Justice Douglas Hikers March For Tenth Year" in The Daily Mail, Hagerstown, MD, 1964 April 25 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Letter of thanks from Justice William O. Douglas to Mr. and Mrs. Ralph Donnelly, 1964 April 28 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Letter from Orville Crowder regarding plans for 11th Reunion Hike, 1965 April 16 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Flier on 11th Annual Reunion Hike has times and mileages, and points of interest, 1965 April 24 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Letter from Daniel Ogden of the Department of the Interior to Ralph Donnelly. Reply from Ralph Donnelly to above with suggested trails, 1965 July 16-29 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Badge, hike schedule, list of "The Immortal Nine", and location of all previous hikes, 1966 April 22 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Sketch of "Grant Conway's Toad" made by Richard Harrison '66, well known cartographer and bird watcher, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Letter from Earl Henlinger regarding navigation on the Antietam and removal by order of the canal company of fish weirs in the Potomac by George Pointer, 1829 September-1968 January 31 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Chief of Engineers announcement of public hearing on Potomac River Proposals. (13 pages), 1968 March 05 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Letter from Donald Frush transmitting County's comments on Potomac Basin Compact. (No report with letter), 1968 March 14 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Program for the 14th Annual Reunion Banquet for the C&O Canal Association contains menu, list of officers and directors of the Association with picture of hikers, 1968 April 27 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Letter from Doug Lindsay to Ralph Donnelly listing the officers for 1968, 1968 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Notice for fall meeting, 1968 December 05 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Letters from Robert Byrd, Harry Byrd, William Spong, Jennings Randolph (Senators); and Saylor, Morton, Broyhill (Congressmen) declining invitations to the 15th Annual Reunion Hike and banquet of the C&O Canal Association, 1969 March 18-27 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Letter from Douglas Linsay regarding the 15th Annual Reunion Announcement schedule and location, 1969 April 07 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Letter from Gilbert Gude accepting invitation for the 15th Annual Reunion Hike and Banquet, 1969 April 08 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Letter form US Senator Charles Mc Mathias declining invitation and enclosing copy of bill to establish C&O Canal Park, 1969 April 19 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Reservation form for 16th Annual Reunion Hike. Letter Kenneth Robertson regarding hike, 1969 April 14 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Hancock News pictures and articles regarding hike, 1969 May 01 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Letter from Paul Hauck to Ralph Donnelly, 1969 May 01 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Letter from Thomas Hahn to Ralph Donnelly regarding sew on emblems, 1969 May 06 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Letter from Congressman Gilbert Gude to Ralph Donnelly regarding 15th Annual C&O Canal Association Hike, 1969 May 09 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Final Announcement on 16th Annual Reunion Hike, 1970 April 03 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Washington Post news article "The Last of the Great Canals,", 1970 July 12 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Sunday Star article and pictures on canal, 1970 October 04 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Cumberland News article "Canal Boosters Here Organize New Chapter," Letter from Colin Ritter and list of members., undated (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Letter from Laurence Halstead Jr. regarding pictures he is giving to the Washington County Historical Society and information regarding the Maus and Spencer families, 1971 February 08 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Letter from Alan Franklin with copy of extensive report on Paw Paw tunnel to be used in Tom Hahn's Along The Towpath, 1971 February 14 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Letter from the Washington County Historical Society thanking Halstead for photos and a copy of "Regulations for the Georgetown Level", 1971 February 15 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Letter from Charles Kirk of the National Council on the Arts to Ralph Donnelly regarding a study of the C&O Canal, 1971 February 17 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Flyer for the 17th Annual reunion Hike, 1971 March 04 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - New York Times article "Old Canals Are Dried and Forgotten", 1971 April 25 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Report "Geology and Engineering, Chesapeake and Ohio Canal Spring Gap to Cumberland" by Geraldine H. and William E. Davies, 1971 April 28 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - American Youth Hostels salutes the C&O Canal Association, 1971 April 29 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Along the Towpath vol.2 no.2 17th Annual Reunion Issue contains directory of assignments and Potomac Valley and Recreation Council flier, 1971 April 30 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Hiking Guide For the C&O Canal, Spring Gap to Cumberland. (12 pages with map), 1971 April 30 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - 17th Annual Reunion Banquet Program, 1971 May 01 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Justice William O. Douglas letter of resignation as Director of the C&O Canal Association, 1971 May 03 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Flier regarding the William Douglas bust unveiling, 1971 June 04 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Letter from William Dwyer regarding the destroying of stone work at "Big Slack Water", 1971 September 29 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Letter from Washington County Historical Commission regarding the widening of the towpath, 1971 October 01 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Article "Blasted blasting" by Bernard G. Charles regarding the destruction of historic features along the towpath by National Park Service, 1971 October 01 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Flier issued jointly with the Canal and River Rights Council regarding a proper development plan, 1971 November (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Washingtonian article regarding damage to the towpath, 1971 December (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Note from Tom Hahn regarding level walkers, 1972 February 01 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Letter from Tom Hahn to John Frye regarding navigation on Antietam Creek, 1972 March 03 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Flier and reservation form for 18th Annual Reunion Hike, 1972 April (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Letter from Don Ramsey regarding notes, 1972 May 12 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Level Walkers Directory, 1972 November (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Resume of Level Walkers Answers to Questionnaire Regarding the Development of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal National Historical Park, 1972 November (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Letter from Don Ramsey with Level Walker Report of, 1972 July 07-1973 February 03 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Along the Towpath vol.4 no.3 contains information on the hike to be held, 1973 March 21-May 05 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Letter from Bruce Wood to Level Walkers regarding a meeting with Supert, 1973 March 23 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Tom Hahn article regarding the "Alexandria Canal Lock", 1974 July 06 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - The Towline vol.1 no.1, 1975 July-August (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - The Towline vol.1 no.2, 1975 December-1976 February (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Flier for the 22nd Annual Reunion Hike, 1976 April 24 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Flier regarding Level Walkers meeting at North Branch, 1976 September 17 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Minutes of Meeting of the Board, 1976 December 12-1977 January 23 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Along the Towpath vol.9 no.3 contains the registration form for the 23rd Reunion Hike, 1977 April (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Letter regarding loan of bill of lading to Park Service, 1977 June 22 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Along the Towpath vol.9 no.4 contains reports of meeting at Poolesville, 1977 April 29-July (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Along the Towpath vol.10 no.1 contains notice of annual hike Paw Paw to Old Town, 1978 April (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Along the Towpath vol.10 no.3 contains schedule for thru hike starting, 1978 April 15-1979 October (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Along the Towpath vol11 no.1 with reservation form for thru hike ending 04/28, 1979 February (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Flier for "daily base " hikers, with mileage table, 1979 April 15-28 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Hancock News article "We'll See" written by John opponent of the canal, 1980 July 02 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Morgan Messenger (Morgan County WVA) article regarding meeting with Jack Fish during which John Douglas expressed his opposition, 1980 August 13 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Bulletin No. 35 American Canals contains report of C & O Canal being designated as a "Historic Landmark", 1980 November (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Along the Towpath vol.13 no.1 contains extensive multiple tabulations of the results of a survey of members residences, ages, habits, etc. done by Robert Greenspun, who was also editor, 1981 January (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Notice of annual meeting to be held at Fort Frederick, 1981 March 30-April 24 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Along the Towpath vol.13 no.2 contains registration form and details of 27th Reunion Hike, 1981 April (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Flier with map and registration form for 27th hike, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Along the Towpath vol.13 no.4 contains announcement of first Fall Hike. Also has charts showing distances and portions of the canal covered by 27 hikes. Done by Robert Greenspun, 1981 October (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Flier with registration form and map for Fall Hike, 1981 October 24 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Along the Towpath vol.14 no.1, 1982 April (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Flier for notice of annual meeting with list of officers and directors, and schedule for all of February, 1982 February 27 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - National Park Service C&O Canal calendar of events, 1982 March (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Announcement of Board of Directors Meeting to be held at the Entler Hotel Shepherdstown, 1982 March 13 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Park Service "Visitor Information" Spring, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Along the Towpath vol.14 no.2 contains announcement of 28th Reunion Hike with map and reservation form, 1982 April (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Flier 2nd Annual Heritage Hike with map and mileage chart, 1982 October 23 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Letter from Richard Stanton to Ralph Donnelly regarding the Hancock Canal Club, 1983 April 25 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - List of officers and directors, 1983 May 01 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Notice of Board meeting, 1983 May 05-22 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Minutes of directors meeting, 1983 May 22 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Development concept plan for Williamsport, 1983 May (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Letter from Bruce Wood to Ralph Donnelly regarding Heritage Hike Hancock to Woodmont, 1983 June 29- October 29 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Announcement of meeting in Hancock, 1983 July 30 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Announcement of final arrangements for thru hike, 1983 August 12 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Announcement of meeting, 1983 September 18 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Minutes of meeting, 1983 September 18 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Along the Towpath vol.15 no.4 contains article on Moore Village Archaeological Investigation, 1983 October (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Announcement of meeting, 1983 November 19 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Minutes of meeting, 1983 November 19 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Announcement of meeting regarding 1984 thru hike, 1983 December 14 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Letter from Bob Greenspun regarding giving talk on thru hike, 1984 March 04 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Tabulation of towpath conditions as of this date, 1984 April 09 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Along the Towpath vol.16 no.2 contains inventory of damage to canal by flood of 02/14-17. Day by day description of points on thru hike. Advice on advisory advisors, 1984 April (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Cumberland (Md.) Leisure Times article and pictures on start of thru hike, 1983 April 14 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - 30 years ago today Sen.Glenn Beall for parkway, introduced bill in 1947, 1984 April 15 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Letter from Bruce Wood to Ralph Donnelly about hike plans and schedule, 1984 April 19 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Board Meeting Notice, 1984 May 20 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Along the Towpath vol.16 no.3 report of condition of towpath as repaired, 1984 July (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Notice of picnic to be held, 1984 July 11-September 16 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Along the Towpath vol.16 no.3 contains Editor Robert Greenspun's astute resume of the "Feckless Land Acquisition Program Of The National Park Service" and reservation forms for Heritage Walk, 1984 October 27 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Suggestions for changes in the by-laws and notice of meeting, 1984 November 20-December 02 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Letter from Bruce Wood to Anne Murphy regarding nominations procedure, 1984 December 04 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Letter regarding cabin at Paw Paw, 1985 January 08 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Notice Board meeting, 1985 January 13 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Along the Towpath vol.17 no.2 contains reservation form for 31st Annual Hike at Paw Paw and resignation of Greenspun as editor, 1985 April (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Along the Towpath vol.17 no.3, 1985 July (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Letter regarding the Douglas papers with copy of report giving recommendations for preservation and storage, 1985 October 18 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Report to Board by Bruce Wood on damage to canal by recent flood, 1985 November 09 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Letter regarding end of service on Board of Directors, 1986 March 19 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Call for volunteers to clean up flood damage, 1986 April 15 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Appointment to Heritage Hike Committee, 1986 April 18 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Letter from Bill Davies letter regarding contributions for repair of flood damage, 1986 May 20 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Letter to the Editor of The Hancock News from Belvin Mann objects to cost of canal clean up, 1986 July 09 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Letter to the Editor of The Hancock News from Belvin Mann objects to cost of canal clean up, 1986 August 20 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Along the Towpath vol.18 no.4 announces Heritage Hike Hancock to Dam 5. Has level walker directory, 1986 October (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Letter from Harold Larsen regarding Ralph Donnelly receiving "1986 Surveyor of the Year" by the Maryland Society of Surveyors, 1986 November 27 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - The Morning Herald (Hagerstown, MD) story on Tom Hahn, 1986 December 29 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Along the Towpath vol.19 no.1 contains discussion of hydro plants along the canal near Georgetown, 1987 January (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Letter announcing election to Board of Directors, 1987 March 11 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Minutes of Board Meeting with copy of Montgomery County Solid Waste Management Plan attached, 1987 March 29 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Along the Towpath vol.19 no.2 contains announcement of the death of Aubrey Graves. Also news that the Paw Paw cabin is beyond restoration, 1987 April (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Minutes of meeting of Board of Directors, 1987 May 31 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Along the Towpath vol.19 no.3 contains description of a canoe trip from Cumberland to Georgetown, and a riverboat trip over the same section of the river. A report on the 33rd Annual Hike is also included, 1987 July (Box 3, Folder 15)